# YOONJOO LEE

# voonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | voonjoolee.com

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI), natural language processing (NLP), and education. I aim to support people to learn from and understand information-dense text (e.g., lecture transcript, scientific article) by structuring the information in the context to create conversational questions and answers to scaffold people's understanding.

#### **EDUCATION**

**KAIST** Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim Sep. 2020 – Present

**Ewha Womans University** Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020 B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

Graduated with Honors (Magna Cum Laude)

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA Exchange student in Mathematics Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Conference and Journal Papers**

### [C7] QASA: Advanced Question Answering on Scientific Articles

Yoonjoo Lee\*, Kyungjae Lee\*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee ICML 2023: Proceedings of the 40 th International Conference on Machine Learning

# [C6] Cells, Generators, and Lenses: Design Framework for Object-Oriented Interaction with Large Language Models

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

UIST 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (to appear).

# [C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

# [C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

# [C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create **Effective Studying Environments**

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

# [C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

# [C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

# **Preprints**

#### [A1] EvalLM: Interactive Evaluation of Large Language Model Prompts on User-Defined Criteria

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Juho Kim

Under Review, 2023

# **Posters and Workshop Papers**

# [P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

#### [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

#### [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, Yoonjoo Lee, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters

### [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Allen Institute for AI (AI2)

Seattle, US

May - Oct. 2023

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team

Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg, Kyle Lo

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee

Nov. 2022 – March. 2023 [C6]

KIXLAB, KAIST

Graduate Research Intern

Daejeon, Republic of Korea Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song

**Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)** 

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019 [P1, P2, C1, C2]

Undergraduate Research Intern, Data Sciences Group

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

Jan. 2018 – Feb. 2018

#### **TEACHING**

**Introduction to Social Computing** 

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis

Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis

Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

# **SERVICES**

# **Program Committee**

• CHI LBW 2023

#### Reviewer

- EMNLP 2023
- CHI 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

#### **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2022

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR

2022

Student Organizer

**Programming Mentoring** *Leader of Student Organizer* 

2016 - 2017

**Mathematics Mentoring in Ewha Girls High School** 

2015 - 2017

Mentor

# HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Research Assistant Scholarship

2019

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

**Admission Scholarship** 

2018

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Last Updated: May 3, 2023

Honors Scholarship College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017
Dean's List College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

**Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship** 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Last Updated: May 3, 2023